# Misael M

Web Developer & Visual Artist



misaelmdev@gmail.com

Contact



**\** 0481165887 Sydney/Brisbane/GDL Reference: On request



www.misaelm.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/misael-mercado/ https://github.com/MisaelMP

## **Biography**

Daniel Misael Mercado Dueñas b. 1988

> Mexican-Australian Full-Stack Web Developer with a diverse background as an Art Director, Curator, and Artist.

Passionate about technology and its philosophical implications, I discovered my love for both logic and creativity through programming. My experience spans both front-end and back-end development.

I also co-founded and directed an art gallery for four years, enhancing my leadership, team management, and organizational skills. My insatiable drive for knowledge keeps me learning and experimenting with new technologies. I am eager to connect with like-minded professionals and look forward to hearing from you!

#### **Interests**

- Agile methodology
- Interactive applications
- •UX
- Web Design
- Machine Learning
- Conceptual Poetry
- Typography
- Editorial Design
- Code Poetry
- Processing
- Spatial Design
- Continental Philosophy

## Languages

English (Fluent) Spanish (Native)

#### **Education**

**2019** Agile & Scrum methodology under Nik Long (PSM1)

2018 General Assembly WDI Grad

**2007-2011** Tertiary Studies, Visual Arts & Art History, University of Guadalajara, Mexico

2008-2010 Course in Ceramic Sculpture and Moulds, at the Institute IDEFT. Guadalajara, Mexico.

_		••	
•	kι	ш	١

O CSS	<ul><li>Javascript</li></ul>	O Vue	O Node.js
O HTML	JQuery	O Three	OPolymer
_	Ruby	_	Bootstrap

#### Other tech + CMS

Jekyll, Less, Sitecore, Wordpress, Middleman, Handlebars, Eis, Nunjucks, Bulma, Postcss, Tailwind, Vuetify, Nuxt.js, Next.js, P5.js, Rails, PostgreSQl, C#, .NET, PHP.

#### **Experience**

#### Michael Hill September 2022 - May 2024 Full time

During my tenure at Michael Hill, I made significant contributions to the main website, where I established architectural patterns and conventions. I worked on various projects, integrating the OCAPI API to support our Nuxt framework. Additionally, I led the rebranding of the site and successfully managed the migration from VUE 2 to VUE 3. I also introduced Tailwind as our CSS framework and provided training to other team members.

#### NRL September 2021 - September 2022 Full time

During my time working with the NRL I updated the main NRL website and team websites using vue apps, handlebars, Fractal and custom css frameworks. I have also been in charge of updating the front end development process and adding new features, like our webpack bundler and migrating some apps to Vue 3.

# **General Assembly August 2021 (3 weeks) Short term contract**

I worked as an Intructor associate helping students to learn how to program using technologies like react.js , firebase, rails and many others.

## Streem June 2021- August 2021 Short term contract

I worked improving the front end architecture using Vuejs, I rebranded the app site, mobile and desktop login page. Heavily interacting with Ruby on Rails API's and Elasticsearch. I used Vuex and Stylus and an integration of guasar and cordova for the mobile app.

#### Process Creative November 2020 — May 2021 Full time

I worked building sites using shopify, liquid, Typescript and webcomponents as the main stack. I role translate the UX design to pixel perfect responsive websites for e-commerce like Just Jap, BC racing, Tropeaka and several others.

#### Ping-Works August 2019 — November 2020 Full time

I worked as a Frontend developer for projects like Mcgrath, Westract, TEEG, MDA, Parks NSW, Resimac and other green and brown projects.

I was in charge of introducing a new arquitecture to work with Sitecore SXA, which was later implemented in many other projects. I introduced Tailwindcss to the workflow, Nunjucks, postcss and other technologies. I also developed many applications using Vuejs and established a set of standards for the agency. My last project involved the architecture and development of an admin portal for TIME ZONE using Blazor the latest framework based on C# and web assembly.

#### Codehouse Frontend Developer August 2018 — August 2019 Full time

I managed all the front-end related matters for a few projects over the 10 months including, PARKS VICTORIA, CEDP and HIA. Although it was a challenging experience, I learned how to work with tight deadlines and deliver on time. I spend my time interacting with the back-end developers as I think it is of capital matter for me to understand the ramifications of projects, and not just what is considered my department. Separation of concerns can be applied to code but not to teams.

#### Full-stack web developer

General Assembly Immersive course 2018. I decided to take a bootcamp full time course at a moment in my life when programming had overcome any other activity of mine. I thought about the idea for over 2 years while learning on my own accord. The experience was gratifying and challenging. I found out how extensive the world of developing is, and how many possibilities are out there, which I find to be a very valuable lesson.

## Co-Founder and Co-director Interlude Gallery Inc. Sydney Australia 2014-2018

I co-founded and managed Interlude Gallery as a Director and Curator. My main roles involved managing the writer's program, curating the shows for the year, the designing of catalogues, invites and editorial publications, a successful not-for-profit incorporated association having reached over 30 collaborators. We worked with over 180 national and international artists and writers, on over 60 exhibitions with a diverse public program.